#### Mboko, David Effiong | Software Developer

Lagos, Nigeria. +2347059337553



mbokodavid@gmail.com





www.github.com/Meekdavid



### **Career Summary**

Full-stack Software Developer with specialty in Backend Development and experience in developing REST and SOAP APIs, integrating third-party APIs, designing databases, test driven development, technical writing, version control, and Linux. Proficient with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Git, SQL, T-SQL, Azure, CI/CD, Wizdler, PostMan, RabbitMq, C#, .Net Core, WPF, IIS, XML, USSD and ASP.Net MVC.



# **Relevant Work Experience**

**Software Developer (Integrations Scrum Team)** 

April, 2022 – Present

**Industry: Guaranty Trust Bank** 

Location: Lagos, Nigeria

Key responsibilities

- Integrated BUA Foods/Cement, UAC Restaurants and other third-party APIs with the bank using C# (.Net Core). Click to view
- Wrote extensible and maintainable codes for new bank's and customer's requirements. Click to view
- Built and amended APIs, to meet up new requirements from merchants and customers. Click to view
- Applied Scrum Agile development to deliver quality application and services.
- Employ the Azure cloud to deliver Continuous Integration and Continuous delivery (CI/CD) of software solutions.

#### **Software Engineer and Data Analyst**

January 2022- April 2022

#### **Guarantee Trust Holding Company Tech Academy**

Key responsibilities

- Utilized Postman, C#, AngularJS, SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), to design and develop software and database. Check it out
- Designed and implemented a C# program for a student registration portal, which automatically updates student information on a database. Check it out

**Software Engineer** 

January 2021 - December 2021

**Industry: Department of Works** Location: Lagos, Nigeria

Key responsibilities

- Analyzed and interpreted collected data using MySQL, Microsoft Visual Studio and SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS).
- Designed and built E-Commerce, social media platforms, schooling, mobile and web applications.
- Developed databases and designed their Entity Relationship Diagrams to enhance mobile and web development.



### **Education**

Software Engineering Nanodegre in Software Design and Development; **ALX Holberton Software Engineering Academy.** 

Overview: Introduction to Programming, Database Management, Machine Learning and Back-end Engineering using Git, Linux, Python, JavaScript, C#, SQL Server, and SQL. Portfolio

2022

# **Core Skills**

- Data analysis/database administration using Microsoft Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) and T-SQL
- OOD, Agile development, solutions architect and technical documentation
- Exceptional ability to work in UNIX, Linux and Windows environment
- Experience user of MS EXCEL, MS WORD, MS power point presentation
- Design and implementation of the web using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Programming with Python, C#, ASP.NET, HTML5, JavaScript, T-SQL, XML, Shell.

# **Awards/Honors**

•	Akwa Ibom State University award for the best performing student in	2017 & 2019
	Mechanical Engineering	
•	Best graduating student in department of Mechanical Engineering	2020
•	Best graduating student in faculty of Engineering	2020
•	Leadership award for commendable contributions to National Youth	2021
	Service Corps in acting capacity as the Corpers Liaison Officer (CLO)	
•	BNET learning scholarship on Data Analysis and Management	2022

#### **Professional Development Training**

•	Microsoft Data Fundamentals Certified	Oct.,2022
•	Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Certified	
•	Certificate of completion of Software Engineering and Data Analytics/Database Management Program by Guarantee Trust Holding Company Tech Academy.	Jun., 2022
•	Database Management Certification View Certificate	Mar., 2022
•	Data Analysis Certification View Certificate	Mar., 2022
•	C# Certified View Certificate	
•	SQL Certified View Certificate	
•	Training certificate on Project Management Professional (PMP) by Exford Global	Oct., 2021

# **Professional Affiliations**

•	Member, Data Science of Nigeria, (MDSN)	March, 2022
•	Member, International Association of Engineers (MIAEng)	Sept., 2021
•	Member, Nigerian Society of Engineers (MNSE)	July., 2021
•	Member, Nigerian Institution of Mechanical Engineers (MNIMechE)	Oct., 2019